Snake, Straw Hat .Halor bel-Nat-Halor,
Chiris, Static, Fire,
Gumbel, Denis, Lennon, Gumbel,
Horsi, vermice, Profit Uro,
Bi-Nat-Halor, Chiris, Dash,
Motel, Gumbel, Horsi, Dash, Oro,
Dash, Dash .Yume no heart,
Umi, nohate, Umi no heart,
But in one head, the one who fights
in the world is still a real world.
I'm not even sure what this means.
But I'm not sure what this means.
But here is the one piece.
All over the people who lead to the dream.
I'm still a man for a long time.
I'm not sure what the body can breathe.
I'm not sure what this means.
All of
If you're connected, the people
of the time will be made.
The world with us will
continue to change the world.
Oh, come on.
That's ridiculous.
You're saying they had a city this
futuristic way back in the past?
Well, it's only a theory.
But there was a man I knew who
risked his life for archaeology.
He shed light on an ancient kingdom.
We found an advanced machine
with a manufacture date
that would coincide with
the reign of that kingdom.
This ancient machine, could it be that
it was made during the blank century?
So you do have some knowledge of it.
Robin, you've heard about this before?
I'm sure this is a rather
painful subject for you.
One that harkens back to Ohara.
22 years ago, the Navy made a
Buster Call and destroyed your home.
I believe this happened
because the scholars of
Ohara learned of the
existence of that kingdom,
which was once lost to history.
What's known as the blank century.
is a 100-year void during
which a war was waged between
an advanced civilization and
an alliance of 20 kingdoms.
The 20 kingdoms won the war.
Later, they founded the world
government, which has ruled ever since.
And in order to prevent anyone from
inheriting that ancient kingdom's ideology,
they erased every last trace of it from
history what that's insane
no way so there's no
record of it at all it
must have been the greatest
story in the world hold
on a second Vegapunk
ohara was destroyed because
they found out about
this stuff right so that
means anyone else who
learns about it will
be erased yes excuse me
then why did you tell us
you asshole it's too late
i do too much i'm gonna
get blank century i
need to forget forget
forget i'll come at you
stupid princess please
calm down as i say it's
only a theory i can't
calm down i'm about to get
murdered!
Let me ask you, Nico Robin.
If Ohara was indeed destroyed
because of this theory,
wouldn't that mean that the government
has essentially admitted that it's true?
In what capacity are you
speaking right now, Vegapunk?
Your employers caused all this.
They wiped out the scholars of Ohara.
Don't you know it's true?
With a position as high as yours,
wouldn't the government tell you?
They didn't say a word.
The rule still stands.
Even if I am affiliated
with the government,
I would still be killed
for speaking of this.
Huh?
I don't want to know!
This is psychological torture, you sicko!
You damned us all!
If that's so, then how?
How did you find out about the kingdom?
The books that Ohara collected in
their library are gone! They burned.
The will of Ohara lives on.
That day, the world was
thrown into confusion.
Ohara was an island of scholars,
revered for its unparalleled
collection of knowledge.
Yet it was destroyed overnight,
leaving just one girl behind.
They were accused of
being a group of fanatics,
plotting to overthrow
the government itself.
Several months after the
incident, I visited Ohara myself.
I was fond of the great archaeologist,
Professor Clover, who had
met an untimely demise.
I wanted to pay my respects.
You knew Professor Clover? Indeed.
He was obsessed with the 100-year void.
He sailed the seas, scouring every corner
of the world for documents about it.
He was arrested and jailed by the Navy ten
times, but they simply couldn't hold him.
Here he is!
Thanks to these tears, he soon became the
most famous archaeologist in the world.
It was no surprise that scholars came
together in Ohara to join his quest.
Soon, the island became the
holy land for archaeology.
You could say his brilliance
was the cause of his death.
The devastation in Ohara
shook me to the core.
Nothing but scorched earth remained.
The once mighty tree
of knowledge was felt.
Its resting place was a
sea of ash and desolation.
As if in a daze, I walked
deeper into the island.
Then suddenly, I saw
something that stunned me.
What is all of this?
A vast number of books
on every subject were
submerged in the lake
at the center of Ohara.
The brave scholars must have
struggled to the last second,
protecting their legacy as
the Buster Call rained down.
This was their parting gift to the future.
Although Ohara had burned, it endured
in the only way that truly mattered.
Even if Marines happened upon the books,
they would be ignorant of their value.
Ohara was victorious.
When I saw it, I couldn't
stop my tears from falling.
I'll be all right, but I need you to
take care of Robin for me, please.
But why?
What about you?
Aren't you going to come with me?
Over here.
Are you...
I can't leave yet.
There's still something left to do.
No, Mom!
You can't leave me now!
I want to stay at you!
Robin, history is mankind's
greatest treasure.
As a scholar, you know this.
Protect the box!
We're off and out of the library!
Save as many as you can!
We weren't trying to
uncover some dark secret.
We wanted to hear the voices of the past.
We wanted to protect them.
Our research ends here, but time
marches on even if Ohara is destroyed.
And as we believe in the past, we also
believe in the future that you will inherit.
What does that mean?
Someday, you will know.
Snake, take her and go!
Are you sure about this?
I am.
Stop it!
I want to stay with you!
Oh, honey, please!
Oh, honey!
You must live around!
Be proud, Robin!
Your mama's a wonderful woman!
Oh, her is a wonderful place!
Never forget that!
It's up to you to pass it on!
Always remember, oh how to
fight against the world!
Rob, are you...
crying?
Jerk!
How dare you make her cry
like that, bucket head!
I'm gonna give you a kiss of my arm!
Nobody makes her eye-yellers just cry!
Damn it!
You're right, Vegapunk.
It's just as you guessed.
Ohara uncovered the existence
of the kingdom. I see.
The books in the lake, where are they now?
I wanted to bring them back
to Punk Hazard, of course.
But if the higher-ups found out, I
feared that everything would be lost.
Fortunately, that day, I wasn't
the only person there in Ohara.
I never thought I'd
find someone else here.
All right, pull it up!
Giants!
But why are they here?
Do they have any idea how
valuable those hooks are?
No, wait!
Why are they taking them?
There's no point hiding.
That head of yours sticks
out like a sore thumb.
Hello, Vegapunk.
It's been a while.
Dragon!
Now that I get a closer look, it
seems you've hit another growth spurt.
Never mind my head.
What are you doing here?
I could ask you the same
question, nice flowers.
Seems I'm not the only one
who's mourning Professor Clover.
He was well.
Small world.
But said again, he was quite
the adventurer in his youth.
That nonsense about him
trying to destroy the world.
The government was creative.
I know.
You must be wondering what
those giants are doing.
The books are priceless.
They can't allow just
anyone to take them away.
Don't worry, I've
already checked them out.
They're not bandits.
Said not.
They came here from Elbaf.
They know what treasures they're holding.
I spoke to their captain.
He's a strange man with
bandages all over his body.
He said, Ohara gave their
lives to save their legacy.
I won't let it be erased from history.
Imagine if your government friends
found out about those books.
They're gonna unleash
hell when you tell them!
Then I what?
I'm not going to tell
them I was making a joke.
But thank you for confirming my
suspicion that you're their dog!
It was naive of me to think
you'd join my freedom fighters.
Of course I thought?
My mind would be vested
on your bury-less army.
An inventor without funds is
like a horse without legs.
Yeah, I got it.
As cold and practical as ever, I see.
The world government is
a massive organization.
You can find sympathetic
ears, especially in the Navy.
We have to keep our eyes on the target.
You know that.
Of course I do.
But this incident hit me hard.
Those scholars were harmless.
All they did was ask questions in
the face of an unreasonable law.
And the government burned them for it.
I'll just have to start a fire of my own.
I always thought you despised Vaughan.
This broken world must change.
And I'll be the one to do it.
In memory of Clover.
For all of Ohara, I will press on.
Later that year,
Dragon bolstered his forces,
recruiting Empire Ivankov
and Bartholomew Kuma.
They formed the Revolutionary Army,
and they've shaken the world ever since.
I can totally see why.
He sounds awesome.
Back up for a second.
You said those giants came from Elbath?
The Think Dragon and
Professor Clover were friends.
And I never had a clue.
Evil, huh?
So he joined up with Luffy's
dad right from the start?
I feel like my brain's gonna explode.
None of this makes sense.
Why did Kuma help us two years ago?
You're the one who modified him.
Can't you at least tell us something?
The books of Ohara must be kept out
of the government's hands at any cost.
Still.
I could not resist making
the trip to Elbaf in secret.
I read every last document there.
And now, the mystery that Ohara
unraveled lives on in my brain.
I've been continuing their research
in secret to this very day.
Vegapunk, I have a question.
That strange giant you mentioned.
It's Sol, isn't it?
He's in hiding now.
No one else can know the truth.
Thank you, Dr. Vegapunk.
You've kept the dream of Ahura alive.
I can never repay you.
You need not thank me for pursuing
all branches of knowledge.
That is the way of a scholar.
Where are these crazy
future shoes taking me?
I'm afraid I can't release you.
But do come along.
There's something I need you to see.
It really hid this robot's cockpit, huh?
Wait a sec.
What if the robot doesn't need one?
What if it's self-piloting?
Let's try talking to it.
It might activate.
Okay, let's see.
Robot, get up and go!
Aw, nope.
Wonder if there's a password. No way.
We just need its name.
I'll guess it easy.
Wake up, Root-gobberts!
Rubinovsky!
Come on.
What are you, like, five?
This thing doesn't work
like a freaking toy.
No way!
Is everyone all right?
I'm fine.
Oh, no.
Robobber, did you explode?
No, that wasn't an explosion.
But then, what in the world was it?
Help!
I request a help!
Wait, Quasar? Oh, Zounds!
I've made a terrible mistake.
I request a help, please.
It's best time to start
while I was wopping?
Was that old man there before?
I don't think so, no.
I am thinking!
Thinking like a fresh egg!
But you made to die!
I don't really get what's going on.
Okay, old man, I'll see what I can do!
Please, my dear boy, get
me out of here! Wait a sec.
This is just like when I met Keenumon.
Quickly now, quickly!
It really is there!
I thought so. It's him!
Thank you.
Your dragon-son, I believe.
I heard that you arrived here.
You and your friends.
And you are Bonnie!
You're all grown up! Dr. Vegapunk!
And the picture of him!
Old man, can you fly?
You can too with those boots!
Your dom shoes are just like mine.
They have a hover function. Really?
How do we use it?
First, press the little
button on the side.
Found it!
And next, take this lever
and push it down. Like so!
Very good!
It's so too high!
I need faith, Marcus!
I'll just hold you one more time.
I'm laughing at you.
I'm going to sing along the same song.
Even if you're a teenager,
I don't want to forget.